Blanchard, Duncan; Papers ua902.065
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Manuscripts, 1789-2003; 1; 9.8 cubic ft.
  - Bubble and aerosol spectra produced by a laboratory "breaking wave" (1981), Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 2)
  - Review of "Field Guide" for BAMS (1981), Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 3)
  - Comments on "transfer of Americium from sea water to atmosphere by bubble bursting" (1982), 1981-1982 (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 4)
  - reply to monahan's comments on "bubble and aerosol spectra" (JGR 86.8085.1981)(1982) (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 5)
  - review of "Field guide" for science digest (1982), 1981-1982; Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 6)
  - water-to-air transfer and enrichment of bacteria in film drops from bursting bubbles (1982), 1981-1982; Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 7)
  - Comments on wu's Science paper (1983), 1981-1983; Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 8)
  - The mechanism of scavenging of water-borne bacteria by a rising bubble (1983), 1981-1983; Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 9)
  - The persistence of air bubbles at a sea water surface (1983), 1981-1983; Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 10)
  - citation classic (1986 and 1987), 1981-1982; 1986-1987; Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 11)
  - surface active monolayers, bubbles and jet drops (1990), 1981; 1988-1989; Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 12)
  - beer bubbles, 1982 (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 13)
  - A book in the night (1983), 1982-1983; Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 14)
  - Book review for BioScience of the hippocratic heritage (1983), 1982-1983; Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 15)
  - The production, distribution, and bacterial enrichment of the sea salt aerosol (1983), 1982-1984; 1990; Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 16)
  - On the production of Aitken nuclei from breaking waves, 1983 (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 17)
  - between the sea and the air: The life and science of A.H. woodcock, 1983-1984; Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 18)
  - The life and sciene of Alfred H. woodcock (1984), 1983-1984; Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 19)
  - Wilson Bentley: The snowflake man (Science digest, 1984), 1983-1985; Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 20)
  - The Orion Bentley article (1985), 1984-1985 (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 21)
  - On the editing of bulletin articles (1984), 1984-1985; Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 22)
  - In celebration of the scientific contributions of Alfred H. woodcock 91986), 1984-1986; Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 23)
  - Bernard Vonnegut obit. (1997), 1984; 1994; Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 24)
  - The rainbow's inverse; color of light scattered by small bubbles in water, 1985 (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 25)
  - recollections of james Hughes (1988), 1984; Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 26)
  - The flaw of electrical current from the ocean to the atmosphere (1985), Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 27)
  - Wilson Bentley: Der "Schneeflocken Mann" (1986), 1985-1986; Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 28)
  - Pioneer studies in the entrainment(a letter to the editor of BAMS), 1986 (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 29)
  - An investigation of vortex rings from bursting bubbles 91987), 1986-1987; 1989; Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 30)
  - window watching, 1987 (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 31)
  - soap bubble meteorology (1987), Undated (Box 3 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 32)
  - The ejection of drops from the sea and their enrichment with bacteria and other materials (estuaries)(1989), 1987-1989; 1997; Undated (Box 4 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 1)
  - More on dew (letter to weatherwise), 1988 (Box 4 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 2)
  - comments on "the laboratory production of the bubbly fraction of the marine aerosol- apllication to polluted seawater (1989), 1988-1989 (Box 4 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 3)
  - bacterial-enriched droplets from bubbles bursting at a water surface (Paul contais book, 1989), 1988-1989; Undated (Box 4 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 4)
  - Bacteria and other amterials in drops from bursting bubbles (ed's book, 1989), 1988-1989; Undated (Box 4 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 5)
  - A tale of two laboratories (ASRC report 1988-1989), 1991; Undated (Box 4 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 6)
  - explosive boiling (letter to weatherwise), 1989 (Box 4 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 7)
  - wind tunnel m.S. (1956), 1989; Undated (Box 4 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 8)
  - Reply to jinwu's comment on "film drop production as a function of bubble size" (1990), 1989-1990; Undated (Box 4 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 9)
  - serendipity and scientific discovery and project cirrus (1996)1989-1990, 1993-1996; Undated (Box 4 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 10)
  - wilson bentley's auroral observations (1993), 1992-1993 (Box 4 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 11)
  - Vincent schaeffer obituary (1993), Undated (Box 4 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 12)
  - The pioneering work of project cirrus 91995), Undated (Box 4 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 13)
  - bentley story reprinted in weatherwise (1998), 1997-1998; Undated (Box 4 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 14)
  - The snowflake man (1998), Undated (Box 4 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 15)
  - wendell mordy obit. (2002), 2003; Undated (Box 4 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 16)
  - Glossy prints of "elec. Of atm"(1963), Undated (Box 5 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 1)
  - M.S. thesis (1951), Undated (Box 5 (1-Manuscripts), Folder 2)
- Research Materials, 1943-2002; 2; 14.4 cubic ft.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Series 2 documents the research Dr. Blanchard conducted while he was working at the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institute and the State University of New York at Albany. The work that he did while at General Electric is mentioned but not specifically covered. The main focus of Dr. Blanchards research was on the nature of bubbles and water drops but he also conduct studies on volcanic electricity and its effects. To conduct this research, he travelled throughout the Northeast and Hawaii. Along with the research he did in the United States, Dr. Blanchard also traveled internationally to collected data. A large part of his international research was done around Surtsey Volcano in Iceland.
  The documents included in this series are photographs, projection slides, negatives, newspaper and magazine clippings, journal articles, correspondence, journals, notes (both handwritten and typed), graphs, figures, drawings, and data (both printouts and handwritten). Folders are arranged and titled to reflect Dr. Blanchards own arrangement scheme. To help maintain his arrangement, the series is sub-divided into titled sections. Since all the sections are related to one topic, they have not been divided into sub-series. Along with this, many of the folders have the same titles that Dr. Blanchard used in his own filing. The titles were only changed if they were redundant and did not provide the researcher with a clearer understanding of what the folder contained.
  - An account of a trip to Irazu volcano in (february 1965), 1964-1965; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 1)
  - Bacteria experiments, Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 2)
  - Bacteria experiments- aging tube (1971), 1970-1971; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 3)
  - Bacteria experiments- aging tube bacteria experiments (1972), 1970; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 4)
  - Bacteria experiments- aging tube bacteria experiments (1979), Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 5)
  - Bacteria experiments- Bacteria attachemnt to Bubble, 1970; 1972-1975; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 6)
  - Bacteria experiments- bacteria exps. 1969, 1968-1969; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 7)
  - Bacteria experiments- bubble chamber bacteria (1978,1988,and 1989) (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 8)
  - Bacteria experiments- bubble chamber bacteria (1978, 1988, and 1989), 1988-1989; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 9)
  - bacteria experiments- centrifugal effects on bacteria in jets (1969), Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 10)
  - bacteria experiments- centrifuge exps (1976 and 1977), 1976-1978; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 11)
  - Bacteria experiments- data on bubbles, bacteria, proposed exps., 1956; 1973-1974; 1976; 1981; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 12)
  - bacteria experiments- electrostatic collection of bacteria- laden drops and a bac/at on top jet drop (23 jan '74-15 may '75), 1974-1975; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 13)
  - bacteria experiments- film drops (1980-81), 1980-1981; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 14)
  - bacteria experiments- hudson river bacteria (1973), 1972-1973; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 15)
  - bacteria experiments- legionaires' disease, 1978; 1980-1981; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 16)
  - bacteria experiments- pond water bacteria in top drop, 2nd, etc. (20 may-12 nov. 1975), 1979 (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 17)
  - bacteria experiments- references and letters, 1950; 1968-1973; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 18)
  - bacteria experiments- rotating tank, 1970-1972; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 19)
  - bacteria experiments- variable depth of bubble release, 1969-1970; 1972; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 20)
  - Bacteria experiments- white, pink, and red S. Marcescens (1973-1974), Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 21)
  - electricity Hawaii, Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 22)
  - electricity hawaii- aerial photos of shore hawaii (1962), Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 23)
  - electricity hawaii- calibration of the vertical fish pole electric field meter, 1961 (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 24)
  - electricity hawaii- faraday cage (1961 on), 1961-1962; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 25)
  - electricity hawaii- hawaiian charge data, 1961-1962; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 26)
  - electricity hawaii- notebooks (1 of 2), 1961-1962 (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 27)
  - electricity hawaii- notebooks (2 of 2), 1961-1962 (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 28)
  - electricity hawaii- potential gradient hawaii, 1961-1962 (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 29)
  - electricity hawaii- rain currents hawaii (1961-1962), Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 30)
  - electricity hawaii- space charge old hospital area hawaii, 1961-1962 (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 31)
  - field trip, hawaii, Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 32)
  - field trip- hawaii- flight data, 1971; 1981-1982; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 33)
  - field trip, hawaii- general data, 1944; 1982-1983; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 34)
  - field trip, hawaii- reports by james sadler and bernard kilonsky, 1981 (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 35)
  - field trip, hawaii- salt inversion data, 1966; 1969-1970; 1981-1982; Undated (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 36)
  - field trip, hawaii- stichting energieonderzoek centrum nederland reports, 1982 (Box 1 (2-Research Materials), Folder 37)
  - field trip, hawaii- weather maps, 1981; Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 1)
  - film drop work, Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 2)
  - film drop work- 3% nacl 3020 data on film drops, 1986; Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 3)
  - film drop work- 3020 cn data summary, 1986-1987; Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 4)
  - film drop work- Cn bubble experiments, 1986-1987; Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 5)
  - film drop work- Cn -seawater bubble cluster, 4 cases, 1986-1987; Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 6)
  - film drop work-cn vs. bubble data feb.-may, 1987; Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 7)
  - film drop work -seawater data4.5mm bubble, cn vs. bsl (dec.- july), 1985-1986; Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 8)
  - hilo hawaii- notebooks on platinum wire and sea salt aerosol experiments, 1962; 1967; 2002 (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 9)
  - ideas, 1959-1968; 1977-1980; 1982-1984; 1987; Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 10)
  - north atlantic cruise notebook-data, 1975; 2002 (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 11)
  - north atlantice cruise notebook- graphs, 1975; Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 12)
  - notebook-data on bubble jet drop charge, 1954; 2001; Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 13)
  - notebook- experiments done at stony brook and the niversity of rhode island, 1976; Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 14)
  - oahu, hawaii- lawrence syzdek's notebook on condensation nuclei, 1970; 2002 (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 15)
  - oahu, hawaii- notebook on sea-salt collection, 1981; 2002 (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 16)
  - oahu, hawaii- notebook on sea salt concentration experiments, 1970; 1981; 2002 (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 17)
  - raindrop size distribution, Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 18)
  - raindrop size distribution- comments on S. waymouth data, 1967 (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 19)
  - raindrop size distribution- data cards, Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 20)
  - raindrop size distribution- drop breakup data, 1964; 1966-1967 (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 21)
  - raindrop size distribution- drop collision data, 1966-1967 (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 22)
  - raindrop size distribution- drop distribution data, 1962; 1966-1967 (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 23)
  - raindrop size distributions- errors in intensity calculations, 1966 (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 24)
  - raindrop size distribution- hudson's drop data, 1963; 1966; Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 25)
  - raindrop size distribution- LTA 17 may 1966, nylon screens (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 26)
  - raindrop size distribution- LTA 31 may 1966, nylon screens (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 27)
  - raindrop size distribution- Lta 28 june 1966, nylon screens (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 28)
  - raindrop size distribution- LTA 5 july 1966, nylon screens, Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 29)
  - raindrop size distribution- LTA film comments and data, 1966-1967 (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 30)
  - raindrop size distribution- pouring water from hose to make raindrops, 1966; Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 31)
  - raindrop size distribution- references for drop breakup paper, 1952; 1958-1959; 1966; Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 32)
  - raindrop size distribution- s. weymouth data, 1966-1967 (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 33)
  - R/V endeavor cruise, Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 34)
  - R/V endeavor cruise- graphs of jet drop HGT (cm) vs. bubble age (sec), 1977-1980; Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 35)
  - R/V endeavor cruise- notebook, 1975; 1977; Undated (Box 2 (2-Research Materials), Folder 36)
  - surtsey iceland, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 1)
  - surtsey iceland- correspondence, 1963-1965; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 2)
  - surtsey iceland- iceland trip notebook, 1964 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 3)
  - surtsey iceland- manuscript correspondence, 1964-1965; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 4)
  - surtsey iceland- newspaper and magazine clippings, 1964-1965; 1968; 1973; 1990; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 5)
  - surtsey iceland- photographs and slides, 1963; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 6)
  - surtsey iceland- photographs and slides, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 7)
  - surtsey iceland- postcards and brochures, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 8)
  - surtsey iceland- reproduce photos and figures, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 9)
  - thesis charge data, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 10)
  - thesis charge data- 1ppm- mbl water. Winter (1958-1959), 1951 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 11)
  - thesis charge data- bubble effects(1953), 1952-1953; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 12)
  - thesis charge data- charging by induction, 1958-1960; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 13)
  - thesis charge data- charge graphs, 1954-1956; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 14)
  - thesis charge data- charge work summer (1957), Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 15)
  - thesis charge data- conduction, etc., 1958-1959; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 16)
  - thesis charge data- distilled h20, 1958-1959; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 17)
  - thesis charge data- electric field experiments, 1960; 1965; 1969; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 18)
  - thesis charge data- q vs. age 10 sec, 1959-1960; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 19)
  - thesis charge data- sept- aug 1958 q vs. time, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 20)
  - thesis charge data- space change, 1954; 1956; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 21)
  - thesis change data- various q and salt calculations (1958-1960), 1953-1954; 1957-1961; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 22)
  - thesis change data- where to find various aspects of work on bubbles, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 23)
  - thesis data bubbles, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 24)
  - thesis data bubbles- bubble collapse dynamics, 1967 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 25)
  - thesis data bubbles- diffusion chamber, nuclei from films, etc. charge on film drops and scholz counter work, 1959-1960; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 26)
  - thesis data bubbles- drop q vs. bubble age, 1959-1960; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 27)
  - thesis data bubbles- ejection speeds of drops from bubbles, 1952; 1954-1957; 1959-1960; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 28)
  - thesis data bubbles- jet drop with bubble age; supersaturation of water, 1959; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 29)
  - thesis data bubbles- production of whtiecaps at sea-- percentage of sea coered, 1956; 1960; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 30)
  - volcanic electricity, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 31)
  - volcanic electricity- bucking gradients on rough lava, 1965; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 32)
  - volcanic electricity- charge generation, 1970 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 33)
  - volcanic electricity-charge- seawater on hot lava, 1965; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 34)
  - volcanic electricity- charge- seawater on hot lava, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 35)
  - volcanic electricity- correspondence with tongaririo national park, 1969; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 36)
  - volcanic electricity- current- seawater on hot lava at spencer, 1965; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 37)
  - volcanic electricity- DCB's early work on lava metal (1962-1965) (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 38)
  - volcanic electricity- glacier water tests, 1966 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 39)
  - volcanic electricity- lava, metal, sea water, oil, 1965 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 40)
  - volcanic electricity- NaCL etc. on metal, 1965-1966; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 41)
  - volcanic electricity- notes and reference, 1792; 1812; 1832; 1862; 1924 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 42)
  - volcanic electricity- notes and references, 1951; 1957-1958; 1962; 1964-1965 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 43)
  - volcanic electricity- notes and references, 1966-1967; 1970-1972; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 44)
  - volcanic electricity- nuclei production, salt left on surface (lava metal), 1965; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 45)
  - volcanic electricity- photographs, 1967; 1969; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 46)
  - volcanic electricity- photos of drops on hot metal surace, 1965 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 47)
  - volcanic electricity- salinity vs. current- lava, 1965; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 48)
  - volcanic electricity- seawater hot metal contact?, 1965-1966; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 49)
  - volcanic electricity- seawater/ lava- induction can, 1965 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 50)
  - volcanic electricity- seawater on lava, still pictures and movies, 1965; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 51)
  - volcanic electricity- seawater on rough and smooth hot alum., 1965 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 52)
  - volcanic electricty- temp/ time- seawater on lava, Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 53)
  - volcanic electricity- test at O.V., 1961; 1965; Undated (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 54)
  - weather modification 6th annual report, 1964 (Box 3 (2-Research Materials), Folder 55)
- Correspondence, 1900-2003; 3; 7.8 cubic ft.
  Series 3 focus on Dr. Blanchards personal and professional correspondence while he was working professionally as well as when he retired. The majority of correspondence was exchanged between Dr. Blanchard and his colleagues and discusses manuscripts or research. The series contains handwritten and typed letters, postcards, manuscripts, newspaper clippings, journal articles, brochures, memos, handwritten notes, figures, photographs, and reports. Please note that not all of the files contain correspondence directly between Dr. Blanchard and the person the folder is named after. Some folders contain letters sent to Dr. Blanchard from the persons family members or letters sent to that person from another source.
  - A, 1952-1957; 1959; 1961-1962; 1966-1968; 1970-1985 (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 1)
  - A, 1987-1988; 1992; 1994; 1996-1998; Undated (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Afeti, George, 1984-1992; 1994; Undated (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Alday, Luis, 1959; 1961-1967; 1970; Undated (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 4)
  - Allen, Ronald, 1966-1968 (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Alusa, Alex, 1970-1975 (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Alusa, Alex, 1977-1979; 1982-1983; 1990; 1994; Undated (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 7)
  - American Geophysical Union, 1951; 1953; 1955; 1961 (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Amman, Walter, 1976-1977 (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - AMS Publications Comission, 1981 (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Andreas, Edgar, 1986; 1988-1989; 1993 (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Angel, Martin V., 1986-1987 (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Art, Henry, 1974-1976 (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Atlas, David, 1952-1953; 1955 (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Austin, James H., 1980-1981; 1986; Undated (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - B, 1951-1954; 1957; 1959; 1961-1968; 1970-1978 (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - B, 1980-1985; 1987; 1989-1990; 1992; 1995 (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 17)
  - B, 1997-1998; Undated (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Bachhuber, Carl, 1975-1976 (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 19)
  - Baier, Bob, 1968-1970; 1972-1977; 1982-1984; 1999 (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 20)
  - Balsama, Joseph, 1980; Undated (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Barker, David, 1975; 1977; 1983; Undated (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Barreto, Ernesto, 1972-1973 (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 23)
  - Barret, Daniel, 1997 (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 24)
  - Bassett, J.D., 1975-1976; Undated (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 25)
  - Baylor, Ted, 1972-1983; Undated (Box 1 (3-Correspondence), Folder 26)